(
"ai_sub_version": "2.9.1",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 7,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 15,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600,
"overwrite_system_prompt": false
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch"
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"run": 5,
"max": 5,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false
)
Lazy Dog Night! INUGAMI KORONE 7th ANNIVERSARY LIVE
Yeah
One, two, check, check, check, check, check, check
We show, crown, we show...
Uh-huh
Grateful Days
作詞・作曲 : ACO / ZEEBRA / 谷内研
[Song: Grateful Days
Lyrics/Composition: ACO / ZEEBRA / Taniuchi Ken]
Yeah, uh-huh
Come on, come on, yo, oh
No doubt yo, no doubt yo, no doubt yo
ACO, ZEEBRA, yeah, hot show
Dragon Ash, hot show, come on
Come on, yeah, oh, let's go, yo
Turn up radio そう今日も聞こえるよ
Turn up radio, yes, I can hear it today too
風に揺られ流れる stereo
the stereo sways in the wind
肩で刻む軽快な rhythm
The rhythm is carved into my shoulder
想いをのっけて届けるよ rhyme
and my feelings ride on the rhyme
よく晴れた空の真下
Right under the clear sky
僕らは遥かな未来目指しました
we headed toward the far away future
Master key 握り締め出発
Grasping the master key tightly and departing
雑踏の中 Kick down 一発
one kick down in the hustle and bustle
今思う闘いの日々
Now I think about those days of fighting
感謝することに溢れ出す慈悲
and I feel compassion overflowing with thanks
しのぎを削ったあの攻防戦
That battle that I fought so desperately in
今なお続くここは最前線
still continues now, and the front line is right here
父から得た揺るぎ無い誇り
I got my unfaltering pride from my father
母がくれた大きないたわり
my mother gave me my large amount of consideration
キミにもらう温かいぬくもり
From you, I get warmth
明日への糧に生き抜くために
it's my provision, so that I can live through 'till tomorrow
I got sound, I got feel, I got beautiful days
I got song, I got love, I got grateful days
I got it, yeah
You makes me happy, when sky's gray
You make me happy, when sky's gray
Darling, my darling
Thank you father, mother and my friend
Yes, Y-A-N-Y-M-O-R-E, Zeebra, Kami, Junior!
Yeah! Yeah! Yo!
俺は東京生まれ HIP HOP 育ち
I was born in Tokyo, raised on hip hop
悪そうなやつは大体友達
Most guys who look bad are my friends
悪そうなやつとだいたい同じ
Pretty much the same as those bad guys
裏の道歩き見てきたこの街
Walking the back streets, I've seen this town
渋谷 六本木 そう思春期も早々に
Shibuya, Roppongi, yeah, early in my adolescence
これにぞっこんに
I fell head over heels for this
カバンなら置き放してきた高校に
I left my school bag behind at high school
マジ親に迷惑かけた本当に
For real, I caused a lot of trouble for my parents, truly
だが時は経ち 今じゃ雑誌のカバー
But time has passed, and now I'm on magazine covers
そこらじゅうで幅きかす DON DADA
Dominating everywhere like a don dada
マイク掴んだらマジで No.1
When I grab the mic, I'm truly number one
東京代表 トップランカーだ
The top ranker representing Tokyo
そうこの地 この国に生を授かり
Yeah, being blessed with life in this place, in this country
Jahに無敵のマイク預かり
Entrusted with an invincible mic by Jah
仲間たち 親たち ファンたちに今日も
To my friends, my parents, and my fans today too
感謝して進む 荒れたオフロード
With gratitude I advance along this rugged off-road path
I got sound, I got feel, I got beautiful days
I got song, I got love, I got grateful days
I got it
You makes me happy, when sky's gray
Darling, my darling
Thank you father, mother and my friend
Yo, mic check 1, 2
日出ずる国に僕ら生まれ育ち
We were born and raised in the land of the rising sun
今こうして踏みしめる大地
And now we stand firmly on this ground
常に開く新しい Page
Always opening a new page
旅に出よう それぞれの Stage
Let's embark on a journey, each to our own stage
ここに綴る喜びと感謝
Here we write our joy and gratitude
共に奏でる真の理解者
Our true understanders with whom we play together
つつみ隠さず時代を描写
Portraying the era without hiding a thing
Pressure はねのけて乱反射
Reflecting wildly, brushing off the pressure
注ぎ込もう 溢れ出す感情
Let's pour in our overflowing emotions
いつの日にも絶やさない愛情
Our love that will never die out on any day
ひるむことなく飛び込む戦場
Diving into the battlefield without shrinking back
枯れることなく咲く百合の紋章
The lily crest that blooms without ever withering
やさしい風ぬける昼下がり
A gentle breeze passing through in the early afternoon
虹がのぞいたこんな雨上がり
As a rainbow peeks out after a rain like this
陽の光映した水たまり
A puddle reflecting the sunlight
日々の喜びここに賛美
Praising daily joys right here
この胸の高鳴りを
This pounding of my heart...
歌にのせて
...I will put into song
日々ここにあるもの
The things that are here day to day...
この手に感じて
...I feel in my hands
I got sound, I got feel, I got beautiful days
I got song, I got love, I got grateful days
I got it
You makes me happy, when sky's gray
Darling, my darling
Thank you father, mother and my friend
ルパン
Lupin!
ルパン三世
Lupin the Third
ルパン・ザ・ファイヤー
Lupin the Fire
Let me show you're my everything
夢のこのファンタジー見てな
Look at this dream fantasy
今こそ走る時なんだ
Now is the time to run
(It's show time!)
そこで見ててよ ワンマンショー
Watch me there, it's a one-man show
これぐらいの試練じゃ足んないよ
This level of ordeal isn't enough
僕が欲しいのは物じゃない I steal your heart
What I want isn't material things, I steal your heart
Listen! party people!
僕は人生駆け上がる猛スピード
I race through life at breakneck speed
まるでスキーの直滑降
Just like skiing straight down
核弾頭
A nuclear warhead
決めたことには頑固
Stubborn about what I decide
ゆっくり生きる術なんて知らない
I don't know how to live slowly
ここはステージ 遠慮は要らない
This is the stage, no need to hold back
やることはやりますわ
I will do what must be done
高みの山目指せ
Aim for the mountain peaks
Put your hands up in the air!
それを見つめる君はセクシー
You, watching that, are sexy
甘く とろける まるで チェルシー
Sweetly melting, just like Chelsea
手櫛で髪掻きあげる様
The way you run your fingers through your hair...
僕にとっての女王様
For me, you are my queen
そんなあなたを今夜抱きしめる
Tonight, I'll embrace you
熱い唇をいただく
And steal a kiss from your hot lips
そして何よりも信じよう
And above all, believe
あなたの心狂おしい程
Your heart, almost to madness
It's a party night! Yeah!
Dancin' with us! Oh oh oh
Everybody don't stop dance! Let's go! Just do it!
茨の道だろうが
Even if it's a thorny path
凍てつく夜だろうが
Even if it's a freezing night
不可能が可能になるさ
The impossible will become possible
君と二人で
Just you and me
ルパンザファイヤー
Lupin the Fire!
だからそうだから 誰にも手にしたことないお宝もらう
That's right, so I will take the treasure that no one has ever laid hands on
狙った獲物は逃がさない
I won't let the targeted prey escape
それがなんだろうとお宝
No matter what it is, I'll steal it
先の先まで計算立てて
Calculating far ahead
瞬時にひらめく名案
Instantly flashing a brilliant idea
そしてあっと思ったらもう居ない
And in the blink of an eye, I'm already gone
もはや芸術ばりの盗みの美学
The aesthetics of theft, which is almost an art form
Put your hands up in the air!
Let me show you're my everything
夢のこのファンタジーを見てな
Look at this dream fantasy
今こそ走るときなんだ
Now is the time to run
(It's show time!)
そこで見ててよワンマンショー
Watch me from there, my one-man show
これぐらいの試練じゃ足んないよ
This level of trial isn't enough
僕がほしいのは物じゃない
What I want is not a thing
I steal your heart
絶対に逃がさん！
I will absolutely not let you escape!
無駄な抵抗はやめて大人しく縄にかかれ、ルパン！逃がさんぞー！
Give up your futile resistance and quietly surrender, Lupin! I won't let you get away!
誰かが居ないと張り合えない
Without someone, there's no competition
相手が居てこそ間違いない
Having an opponent is surely necessary
身近にゃ素敵なライバル
A wonderful rival close by
競い合い互いにハイになる
Competing with each other to get high
ファイナルステージだ天の山
It's the final stage, the climax of tennoyama
お前と勝負の演奏さ
It's a battle performance with you
マジで今夜はサシで
Seriously, tonight it's one-on-one
どっちが勝っても文句はナシで
No complaints no matter who wins
Put your hands up in the air!
悪さ、いたずら、お茶の子さいさい
Mischief, pranks, a piece of cake
曲がったこと嫌い、プラスアルファ
Hating crookedness, plus alpha
ラップマスター、ジェダイも目じゃない
Rap master, even Jedi can't compare
しかし可愛い女にも目がない
But also can't resist cute girls
Oh baby それは演技？ or 本気？
Oh baby, is that acting? or real?
僕は君に一本気
I am single-minded about you
一本道走り続けます
I will continue to run down this single path
空へ飛ぶパス、今日から明日
A pass flying to the sky, from today to tomorrow
It's a party night! Yeah!
Dancin' with us! Oh oh oh
Everybody don't stop dance! Let's go! Just do it!
茨の道だろうが
Even if it's a thorny path
凍てつく夜だろうが
Even if it's a freezing night
不可能が可能になるさ
The impossible will become possible
君と二人で
Just you and me
ルパンザファイヤー
Lupin the Fire!
Let me show you're my everything
夢のこのファンタジーを見てな
Look at this dream fantasy
今こそ走るときなんだ
Now is the time to run
(It's show time!)
そこで見ててよワンマンショー
Watch me from there, my one-man show
これぐらいの試練じゃ足んないよ
This level of trial isn't enough
僕がほしいのは物じゃない
What I want is not a thing
あなたのハート
Your heart
愛すべき 仲間や 家族がいる
I have lovable comrades and family
信念や プライドを 曲げずに 貫くべし！
One must stick to one's beliefs and pride without bending!
ルパンザファイヤー
Lupin the Fire!
Let me show you're my everything
眩しい眼差しを受けて
Receiving your dazzling gaze
君のために今日を捨てるよ
I'll throw away today for you
(It's show time!)
世界で一人の最愛の
To the only beloved one in the world
君自身に気持ち伝えたいよ
I want to convey my feelings to you yourself
僕がほしいのは物じゃない
What I want is not a thing
あなたのハート
Your heart
普段はとぼけた三枚目
Usually a goofy comedian
やるときゃ誰より真剣で
But when I act, I'm more serious than anyone
頼りになるぜいざという時
Reliable when the time comes
こうなりたい誰が見ても素敵
Want to be like this, wonderful in anyone's eyes
知性備えたスーパーマン
A superman endowed with intellect
横にはお決まりスーパーウーマン
Next to him, the usual superwoman
残り二小節ラストスパート
Two bars left, the last spurt
憧れの男 Lupin The Third. Yeah!
The man of admiration, Lupin the Third. Yeah!
獲物は確かにいただいたぜ
I've definitely taken the prey
はい！ということで、グレートフルデイズとルパンザファイヤー、2曲続けて聴いていただきました！
Yes! So, you just heard "Grateful Days" and "Lupin the Fire", two songs in a row!
グレートフルデイズはですね、えーっと、男性2人と女性1人の曲なんですけど、女性のところはね、絶対あずちゃんが良いということで、あずちゃん。で、ラップパートはもう、ノエルちゃんの顔しか浮かばなかったので、
"Grateful Days" is a song for two men and one woman. For the female part, I absolutely wanted Azu-chan, so I got Azu-chan. And for the rap part, only Noel-chan's face came to mind...
ノエルちゃんにお願いしました。二人とも、ありがとう！
...so I asked Noel-chan. Thank you to both of you!
でね、ルパンの映像が流れてみんなびっくりしたんじゃない？ころねもびっくりした。
And the Lupin video played, weren't you all surprised? Korone was surprised too.
で、今日のハッシュタグは、もうね、7周年だって。凄いよね。この上のハッシュタグ「#戌神ころね7周年」で、ぜひいっぱい呟いてください。スクショも大丈夫だよ。
And today's hashtag, yes, it's the 7th anniversary. Amazing, isn't it? Please tweet a lot using the hashtag above, "#InugamiKorone7thAnniversary". Screenshots are totally fine too.
ね、ここのステージ、なんか今日は違った感じだけど、ここはどこなんでしょうか。どこ？
Hey, this stage looks a bit different today, but where are we? Where?
イヌバレー！
Inu Valley!
素敵。今日はイヌバレーから、えー、すべてお送りしますので、よろしくお願いします。
Lovely. Today, we'll be bringing you everything from Inu Valley, so please look forward to it.
って思ったらさ、なんか画面小さくない？って思ったよね、リスナーさんもね。ころねもちょっと思ったので、
Wait, is it just me, or is the screen a bit small? You guys thought so too, right? Korone also thought so, so...
ちょっとね、あ、ちょっと待って！なんか、縮まってる！縮まってる！やめて！やめて！やばい！やばい！縦画になっちゃうよ、これ。
...I'll... Ah, wait! Wait! The screen borders are shrinking! They are shrinking! Stop! Stop! Oh no! Oh no! It's going to turn into a vertical video!
ちょっと押して、今は令和なのでね、画面を広く使いたいので、あっち行け。もうちょっとあっち行け。もうちょっと。
Let me push it back. Since we are in the Reiwa era, I want to use a widescreen. Go away! Go away a bit more! A bit more!
もうちょっと。おっけ、おっけ、おっけ。こっちは？あっち行け！
A bit more. Okay, okay, okay. What about this side? Go away!
あ、そんなにころねと居たいの？おいで。ふふ、本当に来るんじゃねえよ！本当に来んじゃねえよ！
Oh, do you want to be with Korone that much? Come here then. Hehe, don't actually come! Don't actually come here!
行ってきよ、早く！
Go on, hurry!
行った？
Did they go?
行ったね。なんだったんだろうね。
They're gone. I wonder what that was.
あ、なんか... なんか落ちてきたよ！
Oh, something... something's falling!
花びらかな、これ。
Is this a flower petal?
こっちから降ってきた？
Did it fall from over here?
ちょっと行ってみよう！
Let's go check it out!
さくら (作詞・作曲：ケツメイシ)
Sakura (Lyrics/Composition: Ketsumeishi)
さくら舞い散る中に忘れた記憶と
In the falling cherry blossoms, forgotten memories...
君の声が戻ってくる
and your voice come back to me.
吹き止まない春の風
The spring wind that won't stop blowing,
あの頃のままで
just as it was back then.
君が風に舞う髪かき分けた時の
The pale scent of your hair when you brushed it in the wind...
淡い香り戻ってくる
will come back to me.
二人約束した
Just as we were back then,
あの頃のままで
when we made a promise.
ヒュルリーラ ヒュルリーラ
Hyururiira hyururiira...
ヒュルリーラ...
Hyururiira...
さくら散りだす 思い出す 意味なく
Cherry blossoms start to fall, reminding me for no reason
灯り出す あの頃 また気になる
Those days begin to light up, weighing on my mind again
変わらない香り 景色 風
The same scent, scenery, and wind
違うのは君がいないだけ
The only difference is that you're not here
ここに立つと甦る こみ上げる記憶 読み返す
Standing here revives them, as I reread the welling memories
春風に舞う長い髪 たわいないことでまた騒いだり
Your long hair dancing in the spring breeze, making a fuss over silly things again
さくら木の真下 語り明かした
Right beneath the cherry blossom tree, we talked all night
思い出は俺 輝いた証だ
Those memories are proof of the shine I once had
さくら散る頃 出会い 別れ
We met and parted around the time the cherry blossoms fall
それでもここ まだ変わらぬままで
Even so, this place remains unchanged
咲かした芽 君 離した手
The buds that bloomed, and the hand I let go of yours
いつしか別れ 交わしたね
Before we knew it, we parted ways, didn't we?
さくら舞う季節に 取り戻す
In the season of dancing cherry blossoms, I will take it back
あの頃 そして君 呼び起こす
Those days, and evoke your presence once more
花びら舞い散る
Petals dance and scatter...
記憶舞い戻る
memories come rushing back.
花びら舞い散る
Petals dance and scatter...
記憶舞い戻る
memories come rushing back.
気付けばまた この季節で
Before I know it, it's this season again
君との思い出に誘われ
Lured by memories of you
心の扉たたいた
I knocked on the door of my heart
手ですり抜けた花びら
But the petals slipped through my fingers
初めて分かった 俺若かった
For the first time I understood, I was so young
この場所来るまで分からなかったが
I didn't get it until I came to this place
此処だけは今も何故 運命のように香る風
But why is it that only here, the wind still scents of destiny?
暖かい陽の光がこぼれる
Warm sunlight spills down
目を閉じればあの日戻れる
If I close my eyes, I can return to that day
いつしか君の面影は
Before I know it, your silhouette...
消えてしまうよ 何処かへ
will disappear off to somewhere.
あの日以来景色変わらない
The scenery hasn't changed since that day
散りゆく花びらは語らない
The scattering petals do not speak
さくらの下に響いた君の声 今はもう
Your voice that echoed under the cherry blossoms is now no more...
さくら舞い散る中に忘れた記憶と
In the falling cherry blossoms, forgotten memories...
君の声が戻ってくる
and your voice come back to me.
吹き止まない春の風
The spring wind that won't stop blowing,
あの頃のままで
just as it was back then.
君が風に舞う髪かき分けた時の
The pale scent of your hair when you brushed it in the wind...
淡い香り戻ってくる
will come back to me.
二人約束した
Just as we were back then,
あの頃のままで
when we made a promise.
ヒュルリーラ ヒュルリーラ
Hyururiira hyururiira...
そっと僕の肩に舞い落ちた
Gently fluttering down onto my shoulder...
ひとひらの花びら
was a single petal.
手にとり目をつむれば
If I take it in my hand and close my eyes,
君が傍にいる
you are right by my side.
さくら舞い散る中に忘れた記憶と
In the falling cherry blossoms, forgotten memories...
君の声が戻ってくる
and your voice come back to me.
吹き止まない春の風
The spring wind that won't stop blowing,
あの頃のままで
just as it was back then.
君が風に舞う髪かき分けた時の
The pale scent of your hair when you brushed it in the wind...
淡い香り戻ってくる
will come back to me.
二人約束した
Just as we were back then,
あの頃のままで
when we made a promise.
ヒュルリーラ ヒュルリーラ
Hyururiira hyururiira...
花びら舞い散る 記憶舞い戻る
Petals dance and scatter... memories come rushing back.
花びら舞い散る
Petals dance and scatter...
花びら舞い散る 記憶舞い戻る
Petals dance and fall, memories flutter back
花びら舞い散る
Petals dance and fall...
人はこれって時にどうしても
When things like this happen, people always
「時間を戻せたら」とかいうね
say, "If only I could turn back time."
でも誰も直せないよ 治せないんだな
But nobody can fix it, it can't be healed.
昔からそうだし まぁしょうがないね
It's been like that since the old days, well, it can't be helped.
きっと先は深くて不安定
I'm sure the future ahead is deep and uncertain,
でもお行儀よくちゃつまんないね
but being well-behaved is just boring.
タイムマシーンに乗り込んで
If I could ride a time machine,
トラベラーになれたら
and become a traveler.
箱の中の猫を思っても
Even if I think about the cat in the box,
後悔だけが胸を焦がして
only regret burns in my chest,
いつもあの猜疑心が遮るんだわ
and that suspicion always gets in the way.
昔からそうだし まぁしょうがないね
It's been like that since the old days, well, it can't be helped.
きっと先は深くて不安定
I'm sure the future ahead is deep and uncertain,
でもお行儀よくちゃつまんないね
but being well-behaved is just boring.
タイムマシーンに乗り込んで
If I could ride a time machine,
トラベラーになれたら
and become a traveler.
どこをどうやってもね
No matter what I do or how I try,
時間ってのは戻せない
you can't turn back time.
レンズ越し未来にめがけて
Aiming through the lens at the future,
ピースサイン伝えてる
sending a peace sign,
今のとこいい調子
so far, things are going well.
青春の1ページも
Even a single page of youth,
たったの1ページで
is just a single page,
自慢の人生のハイライトも
and even the highlights of my proud life
一夜きりのTweetの buzz みたい
are like a one-night viral tweet.
君と出会った日のことを覚えてるよ
I remember the day I met you,
イヤフォン垂らして この曲をきいていたよ
with my earphones dangling, listening to this song.
あれから数えて今日は何年目！？
Counting from then, what year is this today?!
今じゃ足跡
Now that footprints
どこも残るから これは歌詞カード
are left everywhere, this is a lyric card.
載せす鍵かけておこう ＃％＆＄'~＝
Let's keep it locked up and unposted, #%&$'~=
ほらね、聴き取れない！！
See, you can't hear it!!
皆いつもくよくよ悩み
Everyone always frets and worries,
締め切りに追われ歴史を作り
making history while chased by deadlines,
弱さを無理やり ごまかし
forcing ourselves to cover up our weaknesses.
君の芝生は緑 青じゃなくていい
Your lawn is green, it doesn't have to be blue.
アイドル撮られちゃった真冬の空に
An idol got caught under the midwinter sky,
政治家ぶれてブレちゃった帰り道
politicians wavered and blurred on the way home.
とうちゃんローン組んだ みはてぬ先
Dad took out a loan for an endless future,
でも時は全部を流して
but time washes everything away.
人はこれって時にどうしても
When things like this happen, people always
「時間を戻せたら」とかいうね
say, 'If only I could turn back time.'
物理的な仕組みを直せないんだな
But nobody can fix it, it can't be healed.
昔からそうだし まぁしょうがないね
It's been like that since the old days, well, it can't be helped.
きっと先は深くて不安定
I'm sure the future ahead is deep and uncertain,
でもお行儀よくちゃつまんないね
but being well-behaved is just boring.
タイムマシーンに乗り込んで
If I could ride a time machine,
トラベラーになれたら
and become a traveler.
俺ってやつはいつも気づいた時は手遅れ
A guy like me is always too late by the time he realizes,
絵空事ばかりうつつ抜かして
constantly infatuated with nothing but fantasies,
大事な人すら救えない
unable to even save the people precious to me.
だからこんな歌で自分に言い聞かして
That's why I lecture myself with a song like this,
あの時あいつは多分気を使って
back then, he was probably trying to be considerate,
とくに顔色変えず何も無い振り
without changing his expression, pretending nothing happened.
なんで言わないんだってムカついてもね
Even if I get annoyed wondering why he didn't say anything,
やさしさからきてたならしょうがないね
if it came from kindness, well, it can't be helped.
願わくばディスコで
If possible, at the disco
親父と母さんが会った日に行きたいね
on the day my dad and mom first met.
後ろのジョックスに酒かけて
Splashing drinks on the jocks in the back,
息子じきじきにチャンス作ってやるぜ
as their son, I'll personally create a chance for them.
どんなでかい時計だってすべてさ
No matter how huge a clock is, everything
始まりはこんな小さい歯車
starts with a tiny gear like this.
細かいことはもういいや 疲れた
I'm done with the small details, I'm tired.
別に怒ってないってさ未来は
I'm not really angry, you know, the future is...
人はこれって時にどうしても
When things like this happen, people always
「時間を戻せたら」とかいうね
say, 'If only I could turn back time.'
でも誰も直せないよ 治せないんだな
But nobody can fix it, it can't be healed.
昔からそうだし まぁしょうがないね
It's been like that since the old days, well, it can't be helped.
きっと先は深くて不安定
The road ahead is surely deep and unstable...
でも お行儀よくちゃつまんないね
...but being well-behaved is just boring, right?
タイムマシーンに乗り込んで
Let's board the time machine...
トラベラーになれたら
...if only I could become a traveler.
Done
Yo
シボレーのドアを蹴り開けて街に飛び出した俺んた
We kicked open the Chevrolet door and rushed out into the city!
暴力 酒に女 音楽 中指立てる大人の仮面にゃ
Violence, alcohol, women, music—we flip off the adults' masks!
Oh さぁ踊ろう 「今日」という日を生き急ぐメンバー
Oh, let's dance, we members who are rushing through "today"!
足りねぇか? Little louder! 欲望渦巻く路上現場
Is it not enough? Little louder! A street scene swirling with desires!
Yeah いつだってそうだろう? ブルハ 尾崎 永ちゃんが教科書
Yeah, wasn't it always like that? The Blue Hearts, Ozaki, and E-chan are our textbooks!
くたばるまで格好つけてぇ誓ったよあの放課後
We swore back in those after-school days that we'd stay cool until we die!
俺らピーターパン 「またいつか」なんて言っちゃいかん
We are Peter Pan! We shouldn't say things like "someday again"!
嘲笑っとる大人に言ってやらぁ人生はたったの一回だ
Let's tell those sneering adults, "You only get one life"!
胸の奥底 初期衝動
Deep in our chests, the primal impulse!
見て見ぬフリ No, No
Turning a blind eye? No, no!
夢追い 笑われ 傷だらけでギラつく My way
Chasing dreams, being laughed at, glittering on my way full of scars!
Go on!
You should know
Who we are
Forever Young
Hey! Just next to me from now
大切なことは
What's important is...
魂の状態
...the state of your soul!
Forever Young
Hey! It's your turn next time from here
あの日の始めれば良かった
"I should have started back then..."
その次の始めるべき時は今
The next best time to start is right now!
高笑いする都会の喧騒
The loud laughter of the bustling city...
ウケ狙いならば振り向けれんぞ
...if it's just for cheap laughs, I won't look back!
何連呼? 忘れろ? 夢流した便所 見下ろしてきやがる摩天楼
How many repetitions? Forget it? The skyscrapers look down on the toilet where we flushed our dreams!
Oh まるで勝新みたく破天荒 伝説へとアテンド
Oh, wild like Shintaro Katsu, attending to the legend!
怖にゃあ怖にゃあてその程度
"I'm scared, I'm scared," is that all you've got?
捨てろ負け惜しみ 過去の栄光
Throw away your sour grapes and past glory!
永遠なんぞはねぇて
There is no such thing as forever...
いつか天へ召され
...we'll be called to heaven someday.
ペンで書き殴ったこの魂は 2Pacみたく誰かの心を通過
This soul scribbled down with a pen will pass through someone's heart like Tupac!
なぁ 何か忘れちゃねぇか 人生まるで映画 皆がエンターテイナー
Hey, haven't we forgotten something? Life is like a movie, and everyone is an entertainer!
思い出せ思想は現実化する 誰が Highway飛ばすBentayga
Remember, thoughts become reality—who's speeding down the highway in a Bentayga?
胸の奥底 初期衝動
Deep in our chests, the primal impulse!
見て見ぬフリ No, No
Turning a blind eye? No, no!
夢追い 笑われ 傷だらけでギラつく My way
Chasing dreams, being laughed at, glittering on my way full of scars!
Go on!
You should know
Who we are
Forever
Forever Young
Hey! 俺達は今日だって
Hey! Even today, we...
若気の至りのような夢を追いかけて来た
...have been chasing dreams like youthful indiscretions!
Forever Young
Hey! 変わるはずなんてない
Hey! There's no way it'll change!
さぁ 至ってやろうぜ
Come on, let's reach for it!
今日は残された人生で 一番若い日だろ
Today is the youngest day of the rest of your life, isn't it?
半端な覚悟なら ドブに捨てな
If your resolve is half-hearted, throw it in the gutter!
往生際が悪いテメー 笑い飛ばし誇れ Better days
You're a sore loser—laugh it off and be proud of better days!
まだ終わらない
It's not over yet!
終わらせやしない 燃え尽きるまで
We won't let it end until we burn out!
まだ終わらない
It's not over yet!
終わらせやしない くたばるまで
We won't let it end until we die!
もう 夢を追いかけ
Once you chase your dreams...
本気になった心は 自分の指図も受けない
...a heart that's become serious won't even take its own orders!
Forever Young
Hey! その思いから
Hey! From those feelings...
逃れられないなら
...if you can't escape...
自ら向かうだけ
...then all you can do is head straight into them!
終わらせやしない 燃え尽きるまで
We won't let it end until we burn out!
まだ終わらない
It's not over yet!
終わらせやしない くたばるまで
We won't let it end until we die!
まだ終わらない
It's not over yet!
Forever Young
そう 今日という日は お前に残された人生の一番若い日
Yes, today is the youngest day of the rest of your life!
マリン、来てくれてありがとう！/ 呼んでくれてありがとう！
Marine, thank you for coming! / Thank you for inviting me!
うおおおお！
Wooo!
いやマジこの、Forever Youngって曲を、マリンと一緒に歌いたかったの、Forever Youngって曲をね。
I seriously wanted to sing this song "Forever Young" together with Marine, this song "Forever Young"!
あー、それはマリンが、おばさんにならないように？
Ah, so that Marine won't become an old lady?
そう、もうForeverのYoungだって、ずっと言ってるね。
That's right, saying you're "Forever Young" forever.
そうだね、永遠にヤング。気持ちは！/ みんなみんな、Forever Youngだね。
Yeah, forever young. At least in spirit! / Everyone, we're all forever young.
悩んだ？
Did you have a hard time choosing?
うん。
Yeah.
でもマリン今日はね、今日はね、
But Marine today, you see, today...
え、後ろ見て？
Look behind you.
演奏してくれてる！
They're performing for us!
気まずいよ！
This is awkward!
あ、演奏してくれてる、みんなが。
Oh, everyone is performing for us.
乗ってる！乗ってるよ！
They're grooving! They're grooving!
え、ど、どの子と写真撮りたい？
Which one do you want to take a picture with?
え、そんな、一人だけみたいなのは...
Oh, choosing just one of them...
いや、二人選んでいい、二人選んでいい。
No, you can choose two! You can choose two.
可哀想じゃん、選ばれなかったら。
But it's sad for the one who doesn't get picked.
二人選ぼう、二人選ぼう。
Let's pick two, let's pick two.
ころねすきがなんか、３人... wagon
The Koronesuki look kind of...
いいよ、マリンが選ぶね。
Okay, Marine will choose.
あ、マリンが選ぶんだ、うん。
Oh, you'll choose? Okay.
最初は...
First...
待って、写して、後ろ。
Wait, show the background.
みんな下向いて。
Everyone, look down.
細犬さん！
Hosoinu-san!
可愛い！
So cute!
可愛い、可愛い！
So cute, so cute!
じゃあ、まず細犬と写真撮ろうか。
Okay, let's take a picture with Hosoinu first.
可愛いよ。
So cute.
こっちおいで、マリン。こっち、こっちね。
Come over here, Marine. Here, here.
はい、細犬です。
Okay, here's Hosoinu.
細犬はギターかな？
Is Hosoinu on guitar?
ギターですか？細犬ちゃん。
Are you the guitarist, Hosoinu-chan?
ベロの色が、 wagon
The color of your tongue...
乾いてる。ベロ乾いてる？ wagon
Is it dry? Is your tongue dry?
ベロ乾いてる。ちょっと萎びてるんだけど、ベロが... wagon
It's dry. It looks a bit shriveled up...
あ、これ乾いてる。 wagon
Ah, it's dry.
うん、乾いてる。触らないでね。
Yeah, it's dry. Don't touch it. wagon
ごめんね、いっぱい触って。 wagon
Sorry for touching it so much. wagon
え、次誰がいい？ wagon
Okay, who should be next? wagon
可愛い。 wagon
So cute. wagon
あと一人、あと一人。 wagon
One more, one more. wagon
じゃあ、太犬。 wagon
Then, Futoinu. wagon
太犬だね。 wagon
Futoinu, then. wagon
はい、太犬はドラムです！可愛い！ wagon
Here, Futoinu is on drums! So cute! wagon
でかい！ wagon
He's huge! wagon
可愛いね。 wagon
So cute. wagon
ベロの色がちょっと明るい。 wagon
The tongue color is a bit brighter. wagon
細犬より。 wagon
Compared to Hosoinu's. wagon
撮った？みんな撮った？ wagon
Did you take a photo? Did everyone get it? wagon
可愛い！ wagon
So cute! wagon
OKだね。 wagon
We're good to go. wagon
OK。 wagon
OK. wagon
え、じゃあ最後さ、二人でも撮ろうよ、二人でも。 wagon
Well, then at the end, let's take one with just the two of us. wagon
あ、そうだね。二人でも撮ろう。 wagon
Ah, right. Let's do that. wagon
はい、ポーズ。 wagon
Say cheese! wagon
え？ちょっと... wagon
Huh? Wait... wagon
あ、ごめんごめん！やっぱりじゃあね、やっぱり一人で撮りたいみたいだから、 wagon
Ah, sorry, sorry! It seems they want to take photos individually after all, wagon
あ、やっぱりね。ころねすきーだもんね。 wagon
Ah, of course. Since they're Koronesuki. wagon
撮りましょうか。ころねすき、ころさん好き？ wagon
Shall we take a picture? Koronesuki, do you like Koro-san? wagon
好き？ころさん好き？ wagon
Do you like her? Do you like Koro-san? wagon
あ、よかった。え、マリンも好き？ wagon
Ah, good. Do you like Marine too? wagon
間に入ろう。 wagon
Let me get in between. wagon
なんでだよ！ころねすきーなのに、ころさんの隣に立てない気分どう？
Why?! How does it feel to be a Koronesuki but not get to stand next to Koro-san? wagon,og:
嬉しい？マリンが隣で。
Are you happy to have Marine next to you? wagon,og:
嬉しくない？本当は好きなんでしょ？
Are you not happy? You actually like me, right? wagon,og:
やめろよ！やめろよ！
Cut it out! Cut it out! wagon,og:
だめ、もうだめ。帰るよ、帰るよ、もう。
No, that's enough. I'm leaving, I'm going back. wagon,og:
はい、今日はね、今日のバンドメンバーがいましたけれど、はい。
Yes, we had our band members with us today, but... wagon,og:
え、マリンとも最後撮りたい！ / あ、撮ろう、撮ろう。
Oh, I want to take a photo with Marine at the end! / Let's do it! wagon,og:
せっかくね、フォーエバーヤングだから、今日は。
Since we're Forever Young today. wagon,og:
マイク、マイク！
The mic! The mic! wagon,og:
マイク、間違えちゃってるけどさ。
I messed up with the microphone. wagon,og:
マイクね、うん、いいよいいよ。
The mic? Yeah, it's fine. wagon,og:
デカい声で喋ると拾うから！
If you speak too loudly, it will pick it up! wagon,og:
取れた？
Did you get it? wagon,og:
いけてる？ / 太犬...
Is it good? / Futoinu... wagon,og:
太犬、中心として入ってる！
Futoinu is right in the center! wagon,og:
可愛いのが取れたね、ありがとうマリン。
We got a cute one. Thank you, Marine. wagon,og:
ありがとう。ちょっと次の曲があるから行くけど、 wagon
Thank you. I have to go now because the next song is starting... wagon,og:
一人で帰れる？ wagon
Can you go back on your own? wagon,og:
大丈夫、大丈夫、大丈夫。 wagon
I'll be fine, fine, fine. wagon,og:
じゃあ、バンドメンバーのことよろしく。 wagon
Well then, please look after the band members. wagon,og:
え？ / バイバイ！ wagon
Huh? / Bye-bye! wagon,og:
よろしくって何よ、よろしくって。 wagon
What do you mean, 'look after' them? wagon,og:
どんなムードなん、これ。あ、え？ wagon
What kind of mood is this? Oh, wait? wagon,og:
みんな、急いで！ wagon
Everyone, hurry up! wagon,og:
みんな、次の曲だよ！ wagon
Everyone, it's the next song! wagon,og:
のびしろ
[Song: Nobishiro] wagon,og:
サボり方とか 甘え方とか
How to loaf, how to be spoiled, wagon,og:
逃げ方とか 言い訳の仕方とか
how to run away, how to make excuses, wagon,og:
やっと覚えて来た 身につけて来た 柔らかい頭
Finally, I've learned them, my soft head, I've gotten them into my body. wagon,og:
カッコのつけ方 調子のこき方
How to act cool, how to show off, wagon,og:
腹の据え方 良い年のこき方
how to hold my ground, how to act my age, wagon,og:
脂乗りに乗った 濁った目した だらしない身体
Greasy, dull-eyed, slovenly body. wagon,og:
嫌われ方や 慕われ方や
How to be hated, how to be admired, wagon,og:
叱り方とか 綺麗なぶつかり方
how to scold, how to clash beautifully, wagon,og:
もっと覚えたい事が 山のようにある... のびしろしか無いわ
There are still mountains of things I want to learn... I have nothing but potential. wagon,og:
のびしろしか無いわ
I have nothing but potential. wagon,og:
俺らまだ のびしろしか無いわ
We still have nothing but potential. wagon,og:
悪者扱いして来た街で
In this city that has always treated me like a villain, wagon,og:
悪者扱いして来たオトナへ
To the adults who have always treated me like a villain, wagon,og:
変わりゆく俺、鏡の中へ
I change into the me inside the mirror, wagon,og:
尋ねても答えなら yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah
Even if I ask, the answer is yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah. wagon,og:
去る者追わない 引くとこ引いて
I don't chase those who leave, I pull back when I should pull back, wagon,og:
丸く収めたり 軽くいなして
Wrapping things up smoothly, letting them slide easily, wagon,og:
鏡の中でわろてるお前
The you laughing in the mirror, wagon,og:
括れやしなかったわ。たったの三文字で
I couldn't summarize it in just three characters. wagon,og:
日々重くなる足取りで
With steps that get heavier day by day, wagon,og:
自分の歩幅で闊歩してる
I am walking with my own stride. wagon,og:
カマすとこカマす
I do what I need to do, wagon,og:
まかすとこまかす
I let slide what I need to let slide, wagon,og:
割と適当な段取りで
With a relatively loose plan, wagon,og:
やっと分かって来たかも
Maybe I've finally understood, wagon,og:
このポンコツの操縦の仕方を
How to operate this piece of junk. wagon,og:
19の時の「ついに来たか...」より
Compared to the 'It's finally here...' when I was 19, wagon,og:
もっと清々しい気持ち
My feelings are much more refreshing. wagon,og:
隅田川にかかる
Crossing the Kachidoki Bridge... wagon,og:
勝鬨橋を渡る
...over the Sumida River. wagon,og:
左手にスカイツリー
With the Skytree on my left, wagon,og:
右手に東京タワー
And the Tokyo Tower on my right, wagon,og:
俺はその真ん中
I am right in the middle. wagon,og:
サボり方とか 甘え方とか
How to loaf, how to be spoiled, wagon,og:
逃げ方とか 言い訳の仕方とか
how to run away, how to make excuses, wagon,og:
やっと覚えて来た 身につけて来た 柔らかい頭
Finally, I've learned them, my soft head, I've gotten them into my body. wagon,og:
カッコのつけ方
How to act cool... wagon,og:
カッコのつけ方 調子のこき方 腹の据え方 いい歳のこき方
How to look cool, act cocky, stay gutsy, and act our age
脂のりに乗った 濁った目をした だらしない身体
An in-their-prime, cloudy-eyed, out-of-shape body
幸せの体感速度は 早くなるばかり
The perceived speed of happiness only gets faster
傷が癒えていく速度は 遅くなるばかり
The speed at which wounds heal only gets slower
他人に期待をしないのが今の俺の強み
Not expecting anything from others is my strength now
手負いでも進める距離なら 行く 騙し騙し
If it's a distance I can cover even when wounded, I'll go, keeping it together somehow
身の程を知るほどに
The more I learn my place,
胸を張り いつも通り
I puff out my chest and act as usual
でも時にしたって良い背伸び
But sometimes, it's okay to stretch myself
やっと「大人気ない」が出来る歳
I'm finally at an age where I can act immature
小さな枠組み
A small framework,
ただの数字
just a number
縛られずに
Unbound by them,
でも腹くくり
yet steeling my resolve
あの日の俺が立ち止まる
The 'me' from back then would stand frozen
ほどにデカくそびえ立つ
before what towers so hugely over me
隅田川にかかる
Crossing over the Sumida River,
勝鬨橋を渡る
I walk across Kachidoki Bridge
重なるスカイツリー
The overlapping Tokyo Skytree,
東京タワーと真ん中の 頼りない背中
Tokyo Tower, and in the middle, an unreliable back
サボり方とか 甘え方とか 逃げ方とか 言い訳の仕方とか
How to slack off, how to play coddled, how to run away, how to make excuses...
やっと覚えてきた 身につけてきた 柔らかい頭
I've finally started to learn and acquire a flexible mind
カッコのつけ方 調子のこき方 腹の据え方 いい歳のこき方
How to look cool, act cocky, stay gutsy, and act our age
脂のりに乗った 濁った目をした だらしない身体
An in-their-prime, cloudy-eyed, out-of-shape body
嫌われ方や 慕われ方や 叱り方とか 綺麗なぶつかり方
How to be disliked, how to be adored, how to scold, and how to clash beautifully
覚えたいことが山のようにある
There are tons of things I want to learn
のびしろしかないわ
There's nothing but room to grow
俺らまだのびしろしかないわ
We still have nothing but room to grow!
くだんない話と
Silly talk and...
うざったい貴様と
annoying you...
なみなみの 日々に 注がれてく
Everything dumped monotonously into my days
怠いが溢れ出してく
Weariness overflows
飯がまだ届かない
The food hasn't arrived yet
仕事は片付かない
My work is not done
うだつの上がらない 毎日にため息ばかり
Nothing but sighs for these unproductive days
でまたド派手にすっころび
And then I take another spectacular fall
洗い立てのシャツにこぼすコーヒー
Spilling coffee on a freshly washed shirt
前のめりその姿勢だけは褒めて良し
Leaning forward, at least that posture is worth praising
肩落とす並木通り 増えた柄と差し色に
Walking down the tree-lined street with slumped shoulders, amidst the increasing patterns and accent colors
嗚呼 本当嫌んなる毎日だ
Ah, it's really a depressing daily life
やりたくないことやったって
Even if I do things I don't want to do,
嫌々早起きしたって
even if I drag myself out of bed early,
その分素敵な何かが
it's not like something wonderful
訪れるとかそんなわけでもないのにさ
is going to come my way because of it.
今日もまた頑張っちゃうよな
Yet today, I'm going to work hard again.
がむしゃら以外知らないから
Because I don't know any other way than going all out.
不器用で意地っ張りで
Clumsy and stubborn,
馬鹿真面目な僕らに幸あれ
may good fortune find us stupidly honest souls.
重くなってきた荷物をちょっと置いて立ち止まり
Putting down the heavy luggage for a bit and stopping
昨日の事なんざ忘れちまえば同じ
If you just forget about yesterday, it's all the same
浴びるdaylight羽根伸ばし
Bathing in the daylight, spreading our wings
それか月夜にこっそりと吐き出してしまえば良い
Or quietly letting it all out under the moonlight is fine
でもその前にアレとコレの話
But before that, let's talk about this and that
その為には先ずはソレを片し
For that, first, let's clean up that thing
って今は何時？ いやその前に
Wait, what time is it now? No, before that,
今日もなんだかんだ騒がしい毎度あり
today is somehow noisy as always, thanks for coming!
1ヶ月くらい何にも考えずだらだらしていたいな
I want to spend about a month slacking off without thinking about anything
ゆっくり休んで遊んで眠っていたいな
I want to rest slowly, play, and sleep
って思う日もあるけれど
There are days when I think like that, but...
やっとここまできたんだよ
we've finally made it this far!
ここじゃ終われないんだよ
We can't let it end here!
辛いきついもいつかは
Even the painful and hard times will one day
笑い話にできると信じてるんだほら
be something we can laugh about, I believe in that!
今日もまた頑張っちゃうからさ
Because today, I'm going to work hard again
がむしゃらに愛を歌うからさ
Because I'm going to sing of love with all my might
目一杯吸い込んだ空気
Inhaling air to my heart's content...
嗚呼 本当素晴らしい毎日だ
Ah, it's really a wonderful daily life!
やりたくないことやったって
Even if I do things I don't want to do,
嫌々早起きしたって
even if I drag myself out of bed early,
ほんほんの少しの幸せに
just touching a tiny bit
触れるだけで全部全部ありに思えるんだ
of happiness makes it feel like it was all worth it!
明日もまた頑張ってみようか
Shall we try working hard again tomorrow?
がむしゃらに生きていくんだ
We're going to live with all our might!
不器用で意地っ張りで
Clumsy and stubborn,
馬鹿真面目な僕らに幸あれ
may good fortune find us stupidly honest souls!
do my thing, do your thing
肩の力を抜いて柔軟に
Relax your shoulders and be flexible
do my thing, do your thing
あと1ミリ背伸び
Stretching ourselves just one more millimeter
ああ、本当嫌んなっちゃうよな
Ah, it really makes me sick
それでも今を生きている
But still, we live in the present
不器用で意地っ張りで
Clumsy and stubborn,
馬鹿真面目なあなたに幸あれ
may good fortune find you stupidly honest souls!
Longiness
[Song: Longiness]
リーズナブルな完成度＋スケスケまくりのimitation
Reasonable perfection + a completely transparent imitation
あいつになりたくてもがいても
Even if you struggle, wanting to be like him,
底なし沼のように沈んでくよ
You'll sink like you're in a bottomless swamp.
リーズナブルな完成度＋スケスケまくりのimitation
Reasonable perfection + a completely transparent imitation
NickelBurnして火つけて
NickelBurn it and light a fire,
君の心に落とすimagination
Dropping imagination into your heart.
ギリギリでフライできず地獄送りさ
Just barely failing to fly, sent straight to hell.
君が飛べなかった理由を一つ教えたろうか
Shall I tell you one reason why you couldn't fly?
それは目の前のプロップスに心委ね近道した結果
It's because you surrendered your heart to the props in front of you, taking a shortcut...
誰かのあとをつけてるだけだったからさ
And ended up just chasing after someone else's shadow.
未だわからないか最初は気づいてた
Do you still not get it? At first, you did realize.
知らぬふりして自分の道だと言い聞かせた
Feigning ignorance, you told yourself it was your own path.
他は騙せないオリジナルを奏でないと
You can't fool anyone else unless you play an original tune.
過去の自分に足を引っ張られて退場
Dragged down by your past self, you leave the stage.
俺とお前との差は遺伝子レベル
The difference between you and me is at a genetic level.
俺を狂わせた父母祖父母には感謝してる
I'm grateful to my parents and grandparents who drove me crazy.
さらに磨き上げた自分自身にも感謝してる
And also grateful to myself for polishing it further.
なのになんかしてる君 差が離れてくうちに
And yet, you're doing something, while the gap between us widens...
絶望を感じどうせラップやめるよ
You'll feel despair and end up quitting rap anyway.
5年後いや4年後？これ、余命宣告
In five years, no, four years? This is a terminal diagnosis.
現状に満足して威張ってんの？
Are you acting big, satisfied with your current status?
俺ら発展途上でもかっけぇぞ
Even if we are still growing, we're cool.
リーズナブルな完成度＋スケスケまくりのimitation
Reasonable perfection + a completely transparent imitation
あいつになりたくてもがいても
Even if you struggle, wanting to be like him,
底なし沼のように沈んでくよ
You'll sink like you're in a bottomless swamp.
リーズナブルな完成度＋スケスケまくりのimitation
Reasonable perfection + a completely transparent imitation
NickelBurnして火つけて
NickelBurn it and light a fire,
君の心に落とすimagination
Dropping imagination into your heart.
恋焦がれた男達と時をかけた女達
Men in deep love, and women who leapt through time,
上辺だけのお友達がお前のこと甘やかす
Superficial friends spoil you.
命削り のらりくらり 情熱だけを注ぐ歌詞
Whittling down life, lazily pouring only passion into lyrics.
現実に頬濡らす 理想達が雨降らす
Drenching cheeks in reality, ideals raining down.
あれもカスで これもカスで 俺の歌詞で振り向かす
That's garbage, this is garbage, I'll make them look with my lyrics.
ムキになって無視したって 知らぬうちに街を這う
Even if you get defensive and ignore it, before you know it, it crawls through the streets.
体揺らし声を枯らしたって誰も聴いてない
Even if you shake your body and rasp your voice, no one is listening.
導かれて聴いてみても耳は糸を引いてない
Even if drawn to listen, your ears aren't paying any attention.
今日と明日 明後日 明々後日も白紙の中 漁って
Today, tomorrow, the day after, and the day after that, rummaging through blank pages...
思想すらも曲がってる だけど顔は笑ってる
Even my ideology is twisted, yet my face is smiling.
嘘だらけの肥溜めで のぼせるまで浸かって
Soaking in a cesspool of lies until I get dizzy.
空に祈り捧げたって 変えられるのは声だけ
Even if I offer prayers to the sky, the only thing I can change is my voice.
何かあれば孤独気取り むしり取る金
At any sign of trouble, playing the loner, plucking away money.
指で探り めくり 表あれば裏探すだけ
Fumbling and flipping with fingers, if there's a front, always searching for the back.
歯止め効かぬ無駄な愚痴も 全て愛で砕けてる
Even the unstoppable, useless grumbling is completely shattered by love.
もうこんな歌詞は書きたくない 全部お前のせい
I don't want to write lyrics like this anymore, it's all your fault!
リーズナブルな完成度＋スケスケまくりのimitation
Reasonable perfection + a completely transparent imitation
あいつになりたくてもがいても
Even if you struggle, wanting to be like him,
底なし沼のように沈んでくよ
You'll sink like you're in a bottomless swamp.
リーズナブルな完成度＋スケスケまくりのimitation
Reasonable perfection + a completely transparent imitation
NickelBurnして火つけて
NickelBurn it and light a fire,
君の心に落とすimagination
Dropping imagination into your heart.
チチチ チーム友達
Te-te-te Team Friend
チーム友達 チーム友達
Team Friend Team Friend
チーム友達 チーム チーム
Team Friend Team Team
チーム友達 チーム友達
Team Friend Team Friend
俺たち何？え？チーム友達
What are we? Huh? Team Friend
関西 関東 西 東
Kansai, Kanto, West, East
北 南 チーム友達
North, South, Team Friend
チーム友達 チーム友達
Team Friend Team Friend
俺たち何？え？チーム友達
What are we? Huh? Team Friend
お好み焼き 食う 鶴橋
Eat okonomiyaki in Tsuruhashi
腹いっぱい 飯は美味い
Stuffed, the food is delicious
一人じゃ寂しいし電話きたり
Lonely when I'm alone, getting a call
かけ直した後すぐ行く会いに
Call back and immediately go to meet
T-E-A-M T-O-M-O-D-A-C-H-I
チーム友達 チーム友達
Team Friend Team Friend
チーム友達 まざりあい
Mixing as Team Friends
契り交わし 飲んでる酒
Swearing oaths, drinking sake
契り 契り
Swear, Swear
契ろう 契ろう
Let's swear, Let's swear
契り 契り
Swear, Swear
契ろう 契ろう
Let's swear, Let's swear
チーム友達 チーム友達
Team Friend Team Friend
俺たち何？え？チーム友達
What are we? Huh? Team Friend
関西 関東 西 東
Kansai, Kanto, West, East
北 南 チーム友達
North, South, Team Friend
チーム友達 チーム友達
Team Friends, Team Friends
俺たち何？え？
What are we? Eh?
チーム友達
Team Friends!
チーム友達 チーム友達
Team Friends, Team Friends
チーム友達
Team Friends!
イェーイ！イェイイェイイェイイェイ！
Yeah! Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah!
かっけえ！かっけえことじゃねえ？イェーイ！
So cool! Isn't this super cool? Yeah!
見てんのか、ご、ご、見てんのかよ！
Are you watching? Wh-who... are you watching?!
おい！柄が悪いぜおい！
Hey! We've got bad attitudes, hey!
ちょっと、あの...ちょっとね、ちょっとね、
Wait, a little... Just a bit, just a bit,
この帽子のせいとかでね、ちょっとヤカラっぽくなっちゃうけどね。
Because of these caps, we look a bit like delinquents, but...
うん、かっこいいじゃん！でもこういう格好いつかしてみたかったんだよ！
Yeah, but it's cool! I've always wanted to dress like this some day!
今ね、これバチクソ高いからこれ気をつけて。
Right now, this is insanely expensive, so be careful with it.
え、本当に？
Eh, really?
本当にね、今日ね、来たらね、これ用意してあるんでって言われて、「えっ？！こ、これ、何これ？」って。
Seriously, when I arrived today, they said "We have this prepared for you." I was like, "Eh?! Wh-what is this?!"
重たいでしょ？
It's heavy, right?
うん、重たい。でもかっこいい。
Yeah, it's heavy. But it's cool.
あの、ロックリーみたいになってるから今、うちら。
We're like Rock Lee right now, with these weights on.
ロックリーｗｗ　重りつけてるからね、今。
Rock Lee lol, because we're wearing weights right now.
重りつけてるからね、今。
Because we're wearing weights right now.
解き放たれたらもっと動けるね。
If we take them off, we'll be able to move even more.
そう、そう、外したらね。いい感じになりますけど。
Right, right, once we take them off. We'll be in great shape.
え、でも、ころね、5周年おめでとうございます！
But anyway, Korone, congratulations on your 5th anniversary!
ありがとう！ありがとう！5周年なんだよ、ころね。
Thank you! Thank you! It's Korone's 5th anniversary.
ね、すごい、早いよね。
Yeah, it's amazing how fast it is, right?
すごいよね、早い！
It really is fast!
え、待って、みこちゃんの衣装見て？これ誕生日で...
Wait, look at Miko-chan's outfit? Is this the one from your birthday...
はい！履いたやつね。可愛い！
Yes! The one I wore. So cute!
え、後ろも見せて、後ろも。
Oh, show us the back too, the back.
ちょっとあの、今回用意してくれたこの装飾に...
It kinda matches the decorations they prepared for us this time...
なんかマッチしてて、お揃いなんですけど。
They somehow match and look like a set.
めっちゃマッチしてます。
They really match so well.
え、でもそれで言うとさ、ころね、この衣装さ...
Oh, but speaking of which, Korone, this outfit...
ゲマズのイベントのやつじゃない？これ。
Isn't this from the Gamers event?
そうそう、超、超、超ゲマズの。
Right, right, the Cho Cho Cho Gamers...
衣装！可愛いじゃん！
Outfit! It's so cute!
みこちゃん、今日、これが初お披露目なんだ、この衣装の。
Miko-chan, today is actually the first time debuting this outfit.
え？！これ？！
Eh?! This?!
これで、これで、チーム友達でちょっと初...
With this, with this "Team Tomodachi", it's kinda the first...
初お披露目、初お披露目しちゃったんですけど。
First reveal, we did the first reveal like this?
え、でも、いいじゃん、いいじゃん、可愛い。
But it's fine, it's fine, it's cute.
ちょっと、ちょっと短くない？なんかエッチじゃない？ちょっと。
Isn't it a bit short, though? Isn't it kinda sexy? A little.
これめっちゃ短いんだよね、大丈夫？
This is super short, is it okay?
丸見えじゃん。こら！見せるんじゃないよ！
It's totally visible. Hey! Don't show it!
大丈夫かな？
I wonder if it's okay?
しかもね、ころね、なんかさ、めっちゃ胸がパツパツって言われてて、これ。
And also, they told me my chest is super tight in this.
いや、なんか、ちょっとシワができてるの、パツパツで。はち切れそうだよ、なんか。
Yeah, there's like, some wrinkles forming because it's so tight. It looks like it's going to burst.
すごいよね、これね。たぶんサイズが合ってないんだと思う。
It's crazy, right? I think the size probably doesn't fit.
あー、でもそれぐらいがね、いいですからね。え、え、写真撮ろう、写真。
Ah, but that amount is, you know, actually good. Let's take a picture, a picture!
写真撮りたい！ちょっとアップめで撮りたいな。
I want to take a picture! I want to take a close-up one.
いいよ、いいよ、うん。じゃ、しゃがもう、しゃがむか。
Sure, sure, yeah. Let's squat down then.
しゃがむか。
Let's squat.
ヨウ！
Yo!
ヨウ！ヨウ！あ、いいじゃん！
Yo! Yo! Ah, looks good!
ヨウ、ヨウ！スパイダーマンみたいになっちゃった。
Yo, yo! I ended up looking like Spider-Man.
ヨウ、ヨウ！え、サングラスもさ、取ってさ、撮ろうよ。
Yo, yo! Hey, let's take off the sunglasses too for a photo.
あ、そうだね。よいしょ、よいしょ。
Oh, right. Up we go, up we go.
ちょっと待ってね、みんなね。よいしょ。いくよ！
Wait a moment, everyone. Up we go. Here we go!
せーの！はい！
One, two... Yes!
あ、いい！もう一枚、もう一枚、もう一枚。
Ah, nice! One more, one more, one more.
え、アップめで撮る？アップめで撮りたい、イェーイ！
Should we take it close-up? I want to take it close-up, yay!
あ、じゃちょっとカメラをいただきましてね。あ、どう？イェーイ！
Ah, let me grab the camera then. How is it? Yay!
ヨウ！撮れてる？
Yo! Is it taking?
チーム友達。チーム友達。
Team Tomodachi. Team Tomodachi.
俺たち何？チーム友達。
What are we? Team Tomodachi.
どこ歌ってんねんｗｗ
Where are you singing from? lol
え、でもさ、この曲さ、選んでくれたの嬉しかったよ。
But still, I was really happy you chose this song.
やっぱり、チーム友達っていうぐらいの歌だから、友達と歌いたくて。だから誰でもよかったんだけど、別に。友達だからみんな。
After all, since it's a song literally called "Team Tomodachi", I wanted to sing it with a friend. So honestly, anyone would've been fine, since everyone is a friend.
おい！おい！
Hey! Hey!
嘘、嘘ｗｗ　特に！特にみこみこと歌いたかった！
Kidding, kidding lol. Especially! I especially wanted to sing with Mikomiko!
あー、ありがとう。じゃ、チーム友達だからね、当たり前か。
Ah, thank you. Well, we are "Team Tomodachi", so I guess that's only natural.
チーム友達、イェーイ！
Team Tomodachi, yay!
え、でも、そろそろ次の曲なんじゃないですか？
But anyway, isn't it about time for the next song?
あ、そう、もうちょっとね、もうちょっとだけ続くのよ、なんだけど...
Ah, right, it's going to continue just a little bit longer, but...
え、次、どんな感じなの？
Oh, what's the next one like?
え、次はね、あの、パンツですね。
Well, next is... "Pants".
え？パンツ。
Eh? Pants.
パンツ？
Pants?
恥ずかしい、やめて、撮らないで、撮らないで。
It's embarrassing, stop, don't film me, don't film me.
待って、待って、パンツって、この履いてるパンツってこと？
Wait, wait, by "pants", do you mean the underwear we're wearing?
え、みこさん履いてないの？パンツ。
Wait, Miko-san, are you not wearing pants?
安心してください、履いてますよ。
Don't worry, I'm wearing them!
履いてる？あ、よかった、じゃあ。
You are wearing them? Oh, thank goodness then.
え、ころねはまだこれからなのよ、パンツ。
But for Korone, the "Pants" is yet to come.
え、え、履いてないってこと？これから？
Wait, so you're not wearing any right now? Coming up next?
これから。ごめん、みこみこ、これからだから、ころね、パンツ。
Coming up next. Sorry Mikomiko, but it's coming up next for me, "Pants".
え、パ、パンツ？！
Wait, p-pants?!
Don't worry, Don't flex
Don't worry, Be naked
But wear it, Pants
Animal, Naked
Nature, Naked
People, Naked
But wear it, Pants
Don't worry, Don't flex
Don't worry, Be naked
But wear it, Pants
No pants, No fight
No pants, No sleep
No pants, No night
But wear it, Pants
KING NAKED KING NAKED KING
KING NAKED KING NAKED KING NAKED KING
DON'T WORRY DON'T FLEX DON'T WORRY DON'T FLEX
DON'T WORRY BE NAKED BOUND WEARINESS PANTS
ANIMAL NAKED NATURE NAKED PEOPLE NAKED BOUND WEARINESS PANTS
DON'T WORRY DON'T FLEX DON'T WORRY DON'T FLEX
DON'T WORRY BE NAKED BOUND WEARINESS PANTS
YOU SAY NAKED I SAY NO I SAY NAKED YOU SAY NO
YOU ARE WEARINESS I SAY PANTS I SAY WEARINESS YOU SAY PANTS
KING NAKED KING NAKED KING
KING NAKED KING NAKED KING NAKED KING NAKED KING
STYLISH PUSH STYLISH PUSH
I'M WEARING PANTS BUT I CAN POST NAKED
HEY!
Ah, listen up
キラッと光る犬歯がお似合いの口が物語る
A mouth adorned with a sparkling canine tooth tells a tale
リリカルがもくもくと充満し織り成すスモーキーなストーリー
Lyricals billow and fill the air, weaving a smoky story
Let me see
不確かな平穏と確かな不安を纏い彷徨う
Clad in uncertain peace and certain anxiety, I wander
お飾りにゃないことに恐れ戦く
Shuddering with fear that it's no mere decoration
十色の価値観 騒ぐラジカル 何がはじまる？
Ten-colored values, a noisy radical, what is about to begin?
不器用な生き様に心弾む (Ahh)
My heart leaps at this clumsy way of life (Ahh)
I wonder why 理性を欠いたサバイブ 願っても願ってもなくならない
I wonder why, a survival devoid of reason; no matter how much I wish, it won't disappear
I wonder why 危険度ハイなマイライフ Do it again, do it again (Yes)
I wonder why, my highly dangerous life; do it again, do it again (Yes)
Chase, chase, where is my utopia こじ開ける扉 Viva 現状打破なら飛び乗りな
Chase, chase, where is my utopia; prying open the door, viva, if it's breaking the status quo, jump on board
くしゃくしゃの紙屑に傷ついたハート重ねる しわついたまま時を刻む (踊れ)
Layering my wounded heart on crumpled scrap paper, ticking away time while still wrinkled (Dance)
数多のお目目から逃げた Back in the day ひた隠しているファンキーなヘッド
Fled from countless eyes back in the day, keeping this funky head hidden deep down
個性の延長線上にあるギフトも誰かにとってはバグみたい
Even the gift on the extension of individuality seems like a bug to someone else
伏し目をそらし 行くあてもない
Averting my downcast eyes, with nowhere to go
現状 感情 洗浄 出来ず立ち往生
Unable to wash away current emotions, standing at a standstill
抱いても泣いても足掻いても Fall, fall, fall, fall
Whether I embrace, cry, or struggle, I fall, fall, fall, fall
Uhh 放浪 噛み締めて揺蕩う
Uhh, contemplating my wandering, I sway
Hey don't panic, Go too far far far 一歩前に踏み出す アニマル
Hey, don't panic, go too far, far, far; taking a step forward, animal
(aww) Hey don't panic, Go too far far far
一丁前に 超前に 超前に (Straight out)
Acting like a big shot, way ahead, way ahead (Straight out)
WIP aww WIP aww WIP aww aww aww aww
Critical Critical Critical Criti...
Don't panic, Go too far far far
暗闇が Take over さながら予定調和
Darkness takes over, just like a pre-established harmony
覚えたての絶望にほだされ見る見る間に裏目を出す
Sayed by newly learned despair, things backfire in the blink of an eye
…居場所
...place to be.
みんなー！マフィオーサ、ライブ初お披露目どうだったー？
Everyone! How was the first live performance of Mafiosa?
ちょっと、「Pants」と「Mafiosa」で2曲続けてだったんですけど、
I did two songs in a row, "Pants" and "Mafiosa,"
この「Pants」っていう曲めちゃめちゃ好きで、暇な時ずっと聴いてたので、今回歌えて嬉しいのと、
and I love this song called "Pants" so much that I listened to it all the time in my free time, so I'm happy I got to sing it,
ころねすきーにピンクのパンツを穿いて踊ってもらえたのが、凄く楽しかったので、みんな踊ってくれてありがとう！
and it was so much fun seeing the Koronesuki wear pink pants and dance, so thank you everyone for dancing!
はい。でね、今回マフィオーサのライブ初お披露目をしたくて、全部ラップ曲でまとめてみたんですけど、どうだったかな？
Yes. And this time, since I wanted to debut Mafiosa live, I compiled all rap songs. How was it?
ちょっと初めての試みだったから、すごいね、あの、準備段階から今日に至るまでめちゃドキドキで、
Since it was my first time trying this, I was so nervous from the preparation stage up until today,
「みんな楽しんでくれるかな？」とか思ってたんだけど、だからみんなが楽しんでノリノリになってくれてたら嬉しいなと思います。
wondering if everyone would enjoy it. So, I hope everyone had fun and got into the groove!
でね、原曲知らないよって方が結構いると思うんですけど（結構はいないか、いると思うんですけど）、
I think there are quite a few who don't know the original songs (well, maybe not that many),
もしそういう方はぜひ、めちゃめちゃカッコいいので、全部の曲の原曲をぜひ聴いてみてください。あ！
but if so, they are all super cool, so please check out the original versions! Oh!
最後に歌ったマフィオーサもですね、めちゃめちゃ原曲カッコいいので、ぜひみんな聴いてね！
The original version of Mafiosa, which I sang last, is also super cool! So please listen to it, everyone!
はい！ということで、今回もあります！周年グッズです！こちらー！
Yes! And with that, we have them again this time! Anniversary merch! Here they are!
（急に来る）はい、今回はなんと！うすた京介先生に描き下ろししていただきました！ありがとうございます！
(That came out of nowhere) Yes, this time, Kyosuke Usuta-sensei drew these illustrations for us! Thank you so much!
1つずつ見ていきますかね。
Shall we look at them one by one?
最初はですね、YB-2。久しぶりに見ました、うちのブランドYB-2です。YB-2のうすた先生バージョンのパーカーです。
First is YB-2, it's been a while since we saw it. Yes, our brand YB-2. It's the YB-2 hoodie, Usuta-sensei version.
裏面にイラストが描かれていて、胸元に「YB-2」と入っていて、袖に私のモチーフの骨が入おております。凄くカッコいいと思うので、お楽しみに！
The illustration is on the back, with "YB-2" on the chest, and my signature bone motif on the sleeves. I think it looks super cool, so look forward to it!
続いてこちら！こちらはパーカーと同じイラストのサコッシュです。
Next is this! This is a sacoche bag featuring the same illustration as the hoodie.
イベントの時に使ってる人が結構いたなと思って、ころねもサコッシュ出したい！ということでサコッシュも出しました。ぜひ使ってください！
I noticed many people using sacoches when attending events, so I wanted to make one too! Please use it!
続いてこちら！こちらは、ごめんなさいね、ラッパードッグキャップ！こちらはひこさん先生のデザインで出させていただきました。ありがとうございます！
Next is this! This is, excuse me, the Rap Dog Cap! This was designed by Hikosan-sensei. Thank you very much!
ここに私の骨がクロスしていて、サイドには「YB-2」。これもYB-2なので、パーカー、サコッシュ、帽子、全部YB-2ブランドでございます。よろしくお願いします。
It has my bones crossed here, and on the side, it says "YB-2". Since this is also YB-2, the hoodie, sacoche, and cap are all under the YB-2 brand. I hope you like them!
はい次！これはYB-2じゃない、ころねのランダムラバーストラップ！こちらはフカヒレママに描き下ろしてもらいました！ママありがとう！
Next! This one is not YB-2, it's Korone's random rubber straps! These were illustrated by Fukahire-mama! Thank you, Mama!
全4種ランダムで、今回はラップ曲が多かったのでラップをしているイラストもあります。全種類コンプリートを目指して買ってみてください。
There are 4 random types. Since there were many rap songs today, there's also an illustration of me rapping. Please try to collect them all!
通常衣装、YB-2ジャンプスーツ、グッドドッグ衣装、ラッパー衣装です。こちらもご検討ください。
There's my default outfit, the YB-2 jumpsuit, the Good Dog outfit, and the rapper outfit. Please consider these as well!
そして、フルセット購入特典は、うすた先生描き下ろしのポストカード！
And the full set purchase bonus is a postcard drawn by Usuta-sensei!
数量限定版もありますが、めちゃめちゃ用意しているので急がなくて大丈夫です。本当にたくさん用意したので、ゆっくりご購入ください。
There is a limited quantity version, but we have prepared a ton of them, so you don't need to rush. I really made sure we have plenty, so please take your time.
通常版は箔押しの複製サイン入りです。
The regular version has a foil-stamped printed signature.
はい、ということで、今回のライブもたくさん観てくれてありがとうございました！
Alright, thank you so much to everyone who watched today's live stream!
以上、レイジードッグナイトでした！みんな、本当にいつもありがとうね！また会おう！またね！
That's all from Lazy Dog Night! Thank you all so much as always! Let's meet again! Bye-bye!
Ah listen up キラっと光る犬歯がお似合いの口が物語る
Ah, listen up. The canine teeth that shine brightly suit you, the mouth tells a story.
リリカルがもくもくと充満し織り成すスモーキーなストーリー
Lyrical smoke fills and weaves a smoky story.
Let me see...
不確かな平穏と確かな不安を纏い彷徨う
I wander around, wearing uncertain peace and certain anxiety.
お揃いじゃないことに恐れ慄く
I tremble at the fact that we are not the same.
十色の価値観騒ぐラジカル何がはじまる？
Ten-colored values, a noisy radical. What is beginning?
不器用な生き様に心悴む (ahh)
My clumsy way of life makes my heart freeze (ahh).
I wonder why 理性を欠いたサバイブ
I wonder why, a survival lacking reason.
願っても願ってもなくならない
I wish and wish, but it doesn't disappear.
I wonder why 危険度ハイなマイライフ
I wonder why, a high-risk my life.
Do it again, do it again (escape)
Chase chase, where is my utopiaこじ開ける扉
Chase, chase, where is my utopia, opening the door.
Viva現状打破なら飛び乗りな
Viva, if it's breaking the status quo, jump on it.
くしゃくしゃの紙屑に傷ついたハート重ねる
I stack my wounded heart on crumpled paper scraps.
しわついたまま時を刻む (踊れ)
I mark time while wrinkled (dance).
数多のお目目から逃げた back in the day
Back in the day, I ran away from many eyes.
ひた隠ししているファンキーなヘッド
A funky head that I keep hidden.
個性の延長線上にあるギフトも誰かにとってはバグみたい
A gift on the extension of individuality is like a bug to someone.
伏し目を逸らし行く当てもない
I avert my eyes, with nowhere to go.
現状感情洗浄出来ず立ち往生
Status, emotion, cleaning, can't do it, deadlocked.
抱いても泣いても足掻いても fall...
I hold, I cry, I struggle, and I fall...
Uhhh放浪噛み締め揺蕩う
Uhhh, chewing on wandering, wavering.
Hey don't panic, go too far far far
一歩前に踏み出すアニマル (aww)
An animal taking one step forward (aww).
Hey don't panic, go too far far far
一丁前に超前に超前に (straight out)
One step ahead, super ahead, super ahead (straight out).
Wip aww wip aww wip aww aww aww
Critical critical criti criti criti
Don't panic, go too far far far
暗闇が take over さながら予定調和
Darkness takes over, like a planned harmony.
覚え立ての絶望にほだされ見る見る間に裏目を出す
Swayed by the newly learned despair, I see it backfiring in no time.
手招く反逆のアイコン一抹の不安抱くも邂逅
An icon of rebellion beckons, even if I have a hint of anxiety, I encounter it.
平和ボケした連中を尻目に日陰練り歩けば dope dope dope
Ignoring the peace-loving folks, I walk through the shadows, dope dope dope.
What a uhmmm...